{
    "id": "4f210c74c5df4806b2d5729d885e36ff",
    "title": "Articles Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "What kind of …………………… is it?",
            "description": "When a common noun is used in its widest sense, it is used without an article.",
            "answers": [
                "bird",
                "a bird",
                "the bird"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c9b681f0111246f480d7e5ce2c809274"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. is mortal.",
            "description": "When a common noun is used in its widest sense, it is used without an article.",
            "answers": [
                "The man",
                "A man",
                "Man"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1bfa728c1f034c07896178f0b12aefd3"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. grows in many parts of India.",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before material nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "Cotton",
                "The cotton",
                "A cotton"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b524fac0d5a44c258f9b83a8615e2219"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… is a useful metal.",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before material nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "Iron",
                "An iron",
                "The iron"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2c88c28fc8d74c2eb30f4b16fa8401d7"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was ………………………….. of his age.",
            "description": "Sometimes an article is used with proper nouns when they are used as common nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "Napoleon",
                "A Napoleon",
                "The Napoleon"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3975804eb5a74f4a8ef5c86a7c457642"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mumbai is ……………………….. of India.",
            "description": "Sometimes an article is used with proper nouns when they are used as common nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "Manchester",
                "a Manchester",
                "The Manchester"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8d09134037664c6da956bfb144aad36c"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… is its own reward.",
            "description": "Articles are usually omitted before abstract nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "The virtue",
                "Virtue",
                "A virtue"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3db5ab909e244cee84737b5f4aeae0a8"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is fluent in ……………………..",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before the names of languages.",
            "answers": [
                "French",
                "the French"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "25a0052e70894e689e91aafda9bd52f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "My friend is still in ……………………….",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before nouns like hospital and school when the reference is to the primary purpose of these places.",
            "answers": [
                "hospital",
                "the hospital",
                "a hospital"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "65b61f8b1e914542ad6c024c32ca7a2c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I went to ……………………….. to see my friend.",
            "description": "Articles are used before the nouns hospital and school when we are talking about these places as a building or structure.",
            "answers": [
                "hospital",
                "the hospital",
                "a hospital"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "953ea1662da744bc8819acef5f6c7c8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. has returned.",
            "description": "Articles are omitted before names of relations.",
            "answers": [
                "Mother",
                "The mother",
                "A mother"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9b2dbe32b70b4af2a22ed0fc3c367b78"
        },
        {
            "question": "I met him at ……………………….",
            "description": "Here the club is merely a meeting place and hence an article is used with that.",
            "answers": [
                "club",
                "the club",
                "a club"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c08249382c5f40958200f9472612f831"
        }
    ]
}